JACOB ROTH

Richmond, VA

Phone: 540-435-4472 | Email: jakeroth0@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/jakeroth0 | github.com/jakeroth0 | jakeroth0.com

Summary

Front End Web Developer with a strong background in media production and video editing. Proven experience in designing and deploying responsive mobile-first applications, utilizing a variety of web technologies. Recognized for attention to detail, creative problem-solving, and a commitment to continuous learning.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Front-end Libraries and Frameworks: React, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Handlebars.js **Back-end Technologies**: Node.js, Express, Sequelize, Mongoose, RESTful API, GraphQL, Apollo

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, IndexDB

Other Skills: Figma, Agile, Jest, Adobe Suite, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Final Cut Pro X, DaVinci Resolve 17,

Lightroom, Photoshop, Illustrator, Project Management Software

Projects

Robbie for President 2024 | rebrand.ly/r4p

- Built a React app that integrated OpenAl's API, allowing users to chat with "Al Robbie" about their campaign
- Utilized MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, GraphQL, and Apollo for backend
- Incorporated Twitter integration and responsive styling with Tailwind CSS

Tech Pail | github.com/jakeroth0/theTechPail | rebrand.ly/techpail

- Created and deployed a responsive, mobile-first blog site
- Designed UI, utilized MySQL for database. Sequelize as the ORM, and Handlebars is as the template engine
- Authentication built with Express-Session

MarvelousMoves | rebrand.ly/marvelous-moves

- Developed a site for Marvel fans with character information and related gifs
- Integrated data from Marvel's API and Giphy's API, with a responsive UI using Tailwind CSS

Experience

Full Stack Developer, University of Richmond Coding Bootcamp

2022 - Present | Richmond, VA

Developed and deployed web applications, working with a variety of web technologies and frameworks.

Video Specialist, Hope Church EPC

2020 - Present | Richmond, VA

Responsible for web design and development, video creation, and content curation.

Completed over 400 video projects, from concept to delivery.

Owner & Executive Producer, Jake Roth Media Production

2017 - Present I Richmond, VA

Directed and managed over 90 projects, raising over \$400,000 for clients.

Certified Part 107 license holder for drone operation.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate

University of Richmond, Richmond, VA

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate: University of Richmond, Richmond, VA A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript,

JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, GraphQL, and React.

BA, Major in Public Relations and Cinema

Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA